Samuel Flewwelling Papers
Litchfield Historical Society
- Papers, 1799-1868
  - Correspondence, 1851 Jun-Nov (Folder 106)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackey, William, 1851 Sep 4 (Folder 106)
      Discusses Henry Coons' contract and encourages settling with the rail road company soon.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Oct 31 (Folder 106)
      Calvin Gidding is interested in purchasing part of Mrs. Flewwelling's property. Henry Canfield has requested Millard hold funds and the bargain with Beall is not closed for some unknown reason to Millard.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1851 Nov 13 (Folder 106)
      Encloses a draft. The business with Beall still lingers. There is a discrepancy on how many acres on which Mackay or Mrs. Tallmadge is being taxed. The sale with C. Giddings is not finished.
  - Correspondence, 1852 Feb-Mar (Folder 107)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Feb 12 (Folder 107)
      Has negotiated a sale of land to William Gould and would like Mrs. Flewwelling's approval.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Feb 17 (Folder 107)
      Encloses a draft. Would like to be informed about Mrs. Flewwelling's decision regarding a land sale. Has not heard from the rail road company agent.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Mar 5 (Folder 107)
      Has received the Mrs. Flewwelling's deed and will deliver it. Encloses a draft.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Mar 7 (Folder 107)
      Encloses a draft. His health is not very good.
  - Correspondence, 1852 May-Jun (Folder 108)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 May 11 (Folder 108)
      Encloses a draft. Reports on Barnum, French and Sexton, and Warren contracts.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 May 25 (Folder 108)
      Encloses a draft. Reports on Warren contract.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Jun 8 (Folder 108)
      Provides a statement of payments made by Thomas Warren and John Warren and encloses a survey of their property.
    - Survey of property of Warren, T. L. and Warren, J. B., 1852 Jan 5 (Folder 108)
      The survey referred to in Millard to Mackay, Jun 8, 1852 (previous item).
  - Correspondence, 1852 Oct-Dec (Folder 109)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Oct 25 (Folder 109)
      Michael Norton, John Campbell, and Neil Campbell wish to purchase land of Mrs. Flewwelling and Millard requests instructions. Wishes also advice on the taxes charged to Mackay and Mr. Tallmadge on land in excess of 100 acres. Millard's health is better.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Dec 8 (Folder 109)
      Acknowledges receipt of Barnum and Drier deeds. He has had the land surveyed Mr. Norton proposes to buy and thinks it will be a good bargain for Mrs. Flewwelling. Would like instructions. Relates what he has learned about the amount of land owned on by Mrs. Tallmadge and Mrs. Flewwelling and taxes on it. He has held back funds at the request of Henry Canfield.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1852 Dec 24 (Folder 109)
      Encloses a draft and reports that Mr. Norton would like to purchase entire lot if Mrs. Flewwelling approves.
  - Canfield, Henry to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1853 Jan 12 (Folder 110)
    Reports that a man named Finney is interested in purchasing 96 acres in Rockport and suggests she approve the sale unless she has made no previous arrangements.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Julia Canfield and Phinney, Benjamin, 1853 Jan 27 (Folder 111)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Mar (Folder 112)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Mar 10 (Folder 112)
      Provides a detailed accounting of taxes paid for the years 1849-1852 on lands owned by Julia Canfield Flewwelling, William Mackay, Elizabeth Canfield Tallmadge, and Caroline Canfield Mackay.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Mar 24 (Folder 112)
      Acknowledges receipt of Benjamin Phinney's deed. Offers explanation for discrepancies in his account. Provides additional detailed information regarding Mrs. Flewwelling's and Mrs. Tallmadge's taxes.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Mar 30 (Folder 112)
      Encloses a draft and Mr. Phinney's contract.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Mar 30 (Folder 112)
      Reports on a draft sent and encloses one.
  - Correspondence, 1853 Apr (Folder 113)
    - Eells, James to Mackay, William, 1853 Apr 4 (Folder 113)
      Matters related to Mrs. Flewwelling's property insurance.
    - Eells, James to Mackay, William, 1853 Apr 6 (Folder 113)
    - Eells, James to Mackay, William, 1853 Apr 13 (Folder 113)
      Matters relating to Mrs. Flewwelling's property insurance.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Apr 23 (Folder 113)
      Millard responds to Mackay's request for receipts for taxes paid. Reverse has Mackay's calculations.
  - Agreement between Flewwelling, Julia Canfield and Norton, Michael, 1853 May 20 (Folder 114)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Jun-Aug (Folder 115)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Jun 25 (Folder 115)
      Encloses a draft. Happy to hear of Mackay's safe return from Cincinnati. Millard's health is improving.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1853 Jul 25 (Folder 115)
      Discusses Phinney mortgage and Barnum's payment in full, encloses a draft for Miss J. F. Ruggles
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1853 Aug 27 (Folder 115)
      Encloses his draft per agreement executed by Mackay and Mrs. Flewwelling.
  - Statement of an account prepared by Canfield, William, 1854 Feb 5 (Folder 116)
  - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1854 Mar 10 (Folder 117)
    Encloses a draft and deeds. His health has been poor.
  - Power of attorney, Munson, Laura to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1854 Mar 25 (Folder 118)
  - Account, Millard, Royal, 1854 Apr 1 (Folder 119)
  - Correspondence, 1854 Apr-Sep (Folder 120)
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1854 Apr 1 (Folder 120)
      Responds in detail to Mackay's inquiry regarding a tax.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1854 Apr 3 (Folder 120)
      Discusses the payment of taxes.
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1854 Aug 29 (Folder 120)
      Encloses a draft per the agreement executed by Mackay and Mrs. Flewwelling. Discusses the interests of the heirs of P. Cheney in lot 79, which he had purchased from Mrs. Flewwelling.
  - Correspondence, 1854 Sep-Nov (Folder 121)
    - Hilliard, Richard to Mackay, William, 1854 Sep 11 (Folder 121)
      Writes regarding the discharge of the claim involving him and Mr. Hayes. Also remarks on links wanting from the chain of title but is hope there will be no trouble because of it.
    - Mackay, William to Hilliard, Richard, 1854 Sep 18 (Folder 121)
      Responds to Hilliard's letter regarding the discharge of the Hilliard and Hayes claim.
    - Hilliard, Richard to Mackay, William, 1854 Oct 6 (Folder 121)
      He does not have records that indicate there is a balance due as indicated by Mackay, but will consult with Mr. Hayes about the matter.
    - Receipt, Mackay, William from Hilliard, Richard, 1854 Oct 21 (Folder 121)
      Last installment due on his 1844 agreement.
    - Millard, Royal to Mackay, William, 1854 Nov 11 (Folder 121)
      Reports that his long-time bank, the Canal Bank of Cleveland, has failed and he had recently made deposits there. The cashier believes the bank will prove solvent, but that it will take time to close.
  - Statement of account, Millard, Royal, 1854 Dec (Folder 122)
    Statement of Millard's account as of the time of his death calculated by U. S. Bristol.
  - Correspondence, 1855 Apr (Folder 123)
    - Murray, Lucy to Flewwelling, Julia Canfield, 1855 Mar 1 (Folder 123)
      She writes regarding her payment due April 1 and the failure of the Canal Bank.
    - Murray, Lucy to Mackay, William, 1855 Apr 6 (Folder 123)
      Encloses a draft and discusses her payment.
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1855 Aug 30 (Folder 123)
      Encloses a draft per the agreement executed by Mackay and Mrs. Flewwelling. Discusses the interest of the heirs of P. Cheney in lot 79.
  - Correspondence, 1855 May-Sep (Folder 124)
    - French, Collins to Mackay, William, 1855 May 8 (Folder 124)
      Discusses payment of his mortgage. Mackay's response, dated May 15, 1855 is on the reverse. He suggests that French review the terms of the contract.
    - French, Collins to Mackay, William, 1855 May 17 (Folder 124)
      French copies portions of the contract into his letter and insists he and Saxton have done nothing that is not within the terms of the contract. Mackay's response, dated May 22, 1855, is on the reverse. He writes that he made a mistake.
    - French, Collins to Mackay, William, 1855 Aug 29 (Folder 124)
      He and Saxton are ready to make a payment on the land they bought of Mrs. Flewwelling.
    - French, Collins to Mackay, William, 1855 Sep 15 (Folder 124)
      Mackay appears to have misunderstood what French proposed in a previous letter. He restates what he intended and proposes to make payments on the purchased land.
  - Correspondence, 1856 Mar-Aug (Folder 125)
    - Canfield, Heney to Mackay, William, 1856 Mar 27 (Folder 125)
      Discusses French's letter in which he says he will pay up in full for his land and wishes to receive a deed.
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1856 Jun 19 (Folder 125)
      Seeks advice on what amount he should pay for the interest of the heirs of P. Cheney in lot 79.
    - Canfield, Henry to Mackay, William, 1856 Aug 5 (Folder 125)
      He encloses a quit claim deed from Julia Canfield Flewwelling to Clark and Hilliard and discusses the P. Cheney claim.
    - Canfield, Henry to Mackay, William, 1856 Aug 4 (Folder 125)
      Encloses a draft and provides an accounting of funds received and expenses.
  - Correspondence, 1856 Sep-Dec (Folder 126)
    - Canfield, Henry to Mackay, William, 1856 Sep 7 (Folder 126)
      McKanna and Bronson should be notified that they must pay something.
    - Clark, Edmund to Mackay, William, 1856 Sep 11 (Folder 126)
      Discusses the matter of P. Cheney's heirs and lot 79.
    - Bristol, U. S. to Mackay, 1856 Nov 27 (Folder 126)
      Reports that the Canal Bank will pay a dividend to depositors December next if there is any to pay.
    - Canfield, William to Mackay, William, 1856 Dec 5 (Folder 126)
      He reports on inspecting Mrs. Flewwelling's Rockport papers after Henry Canfield's funeral. Even after looking at the papers, he is wholly ignorant on the conditions of the contracts and the lands. He discusses taxes recently paid on lands owned by Mrs. Flewwelling, Mackay, and Mr. and Mrs. Tallmadge. He will need lists of contracts, deeds, and owners, and a power of attorney from Mrs. Flewwelling to resolve matters.
  - Correspondence, 1857 (Folder 127)
    - Demarest, D. D. to Mackay, William, 1857 May 16 (Folder 127)
      Regarding Mrs. Flewwelling's property insurance.
    - Demarest, D. D. to Mackay, William, 1857 Apr 6 (Folder 127)
  - Statement of account, Canfield, William, 1858 May 4 (Folder 128)
  - Correspondence, 1859 (Folder 129)
    - Canfield, William to Mackay, William, 1859 Jun 10 (Folder 129)
      He is in Cleveland to conclude the sale of Mrs. Tallmadge's lands. He encloses a draft. Reports on his busy schedule. Bronson's crops failed last year and he offers to sell his land. Canfield has been unable to find any purchasers for the rest of the lands. The severe cold weather has damaged crops and will amount to millions of dollars and cause great pecuniary distress for two or three years. He is unable to get anything for Mrs. Flewwelling at present. Mentions dividend on C. Ticknor's estate and the Cisco farm.
    - Mackay, William to Canfield, William, 1859 Jun 13 (Folder 129)
      Acknowledges receipt of the draft and says he sent two deeds a week ago. He regrets to hear such discouraging accounts of the destruction caused by the frost and trusts the results will not be so bad. He hopes that Mr. Bronson may succeed in making some arrangement to pay on his account. Glad to be able to sell Cisco farm.
    - Bristol, U. S. to Mackay, William, 1859 Jul 18 (Folder 129)
      Discusses dividend paid by Canal Bank, Mrs. Flewwelling's account, taxes, and closing the account with the estate of Royal Millard.
    - Mackay, William to Bristol, U. S., 1859 Sep 16 (Folder 129)
      He has concluded to settle with the estate of Royal Millard as Bristol proposes. Will be in Concord, Mass., next week and the settle in New York for the winter.
    - Bristol, U. S. to Mackay, William, 1859 Dec 28 (Folder 129)
      Discusses dividend paid by Canal Bank, Mrs. Flewwelling's account, taxes, and closing the account with the estate of Royal Millard. Includes a statement of account taken from Millard's account book.
  - Correspondence, 1860 (Folder 130)
    - Mackay, William to Bristol, U. S., 1860 Jan 14 (Folder 130)
      His reply to Bristol's letter of Dec 28, 1859, regarding the Canal Bank and Mrs. Flewwelling's account.
    - Bristol, U. S. to McKay, William, 1860 Jan 25 (Folder 130)
      Acknowledges Mackay's letter of Jan 14, 1860, and provides a receipt for payment for money advanced by Royal Millard on behalf of Mrs. Flewwelling. Mackay's reply, dated, Feb 5, 1860, acknowledging Bristol's receipt and returning the agreement, is on the reverse.
  - Correspondence, 1866 Jun 6-Dec 3 (Folder 131)
    6 items relating to the sale of the Harding farm in Iowa by Abel Harding, a relative of Samuel Flewwelling, of Racine, Wisc., which discuss family information, a description of the property, and conditions of the sale. Correspondents are G. W. Gilbert, Eliza Harding, Abel Harding.
  - Statement of Munson house in New Rochelle to James W. Todd, 1867 Nov (Folder 132)
  - Trust established for Munson, Maria Louisa by Flewwelling, Julia Canfield from the proceeds of the payment of a mortgage on a house owned by Munson, Laura, 1867 Dec 17 (Folder 133)
  - Receipts, Munson, Laura Louisa and Munson, Fred A., 1868 Jul 1 (Folder 134)
    2 items. Receipts from Laura Louisa Munson and Fred A. Munson related to funds distrubuted from the estate of Julia Canfield Flewwelling and the payment of a mortgage on property owned by Laura Munson.
  - List of a lease and deeds, undated (Folder 135)
    Lists a lease and deeds involving Samuel Flewwelling, Julia Canfield Flewwelling, Henry Canfield, Frederick Tallmadge, Elizabeth Canfield Tallmadge, William Lane, and Pamela Hubbell Lane.
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Folder 136)
    - List of lands [fragment], undated (Folder 136)
      List of acreage in various sections that ought to be quit claimed by the State of Connecticut to Judson Canfield.
    - Sketch of lots on Boardman Road and Canfield Street, undated (Folder 136)
    - Wrapper, memo. of contracts for land [accounts] made by S. F. [Samuel Flewwelling], undated (Folder 136)
      In William Mackay's hand.
  - delete (Folder 1000)